Guide to the A. Henry Detweiler papers, [ca. 1924]-1970.
Detweiler, A. Henry papers
- Series IV. General Documents and Material
  - Miscellaneous Maps, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1945-1964; Includes English ration books 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Address Books, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Photo Album, 1897-1914 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Photo Album, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photo Album, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photo Album, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photo Album, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Journals, 1953-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Architecture of Gramercy Park, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Knossos Maps/Drawings, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Catalog Cards, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Catalog Cards, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Catalog Cards, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Papers Associated with Detweiler's Attempt to Get Naval Commission, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Scholarship Correspondence, 1928-1940 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with Archaeologists, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cornell University Administrative Matters, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - New York City Program Papers, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - General Notes, 1926-1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - General Notes, 1925-1942 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Laboratory Exercises in Elementary Chemistry, 1923-1924 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Postcards, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Notebooks, Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Detweiler Notes and Papers, 1935-1945 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Financial Records, 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Notebooks, 1935-1969 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Medal from Pavia, Italy (?) in blue bag, 1961-11 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Archeologia Journals, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Archaeology Journals, 1922-1964 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Progress Report by Watertown, NY City Planning Commission, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Catalog Cards, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Catalog Cards, Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Catalog Cards, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Encyclopedie ou Dictionnaire Raisonne des Sciences, des Arts, et des Metiers, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Journals, 1957-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Maps of Middle East, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings about AHD, 1947-1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Brochures, Undated; Includes English ration books 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - An Interim Report on the City of Bethlehem, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bank Statements, 1965-1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Award given to The University of Pavia, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Dura Excavation Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Appointment Books, 1938-1941 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - A.H.D. Passports, 1936-1961 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Licenses and Visas, 1931-1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Books, 1944-1949 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Appointment Books, 1944-1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Appointment Books, 1957-1963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Appointment Books, 1959-1962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Appointment Books, 1953-1956 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Appointment Books, 1953-1956 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Appointment Books, 1950-1952 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Appointment Books, 1963-1966 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Appointment Books, 1967-1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Itinerary and Film Negatives, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Research in Italian Architecture Style, Undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Photo Survey of Romanesque Architecture, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Early Christian Architecture, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Lecture: Early Christian Architecture, Undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lecture Notes, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Lecture Notes, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Lecture given to Saturday Night Club, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Lecture No. I, Undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Lecture No. II, Undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Lecture No. III, Undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Lecture No. IV, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Lecture No. V, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Book Chapter Drafts, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Oberlin Lecture and 1st Chapter Outline, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - ASOR Publications on Gerasa, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Architecture Lecture II and III and V Slides: The Levant, Undated (Box 16, Folder A)
  - Architecture Lecture I Slides: Maps, Dura, and Sardis Excavations, Undated (Box 16, Folder B)
  - Architecture Lecture I and IV Slides: Jerash (Gerasa), Undated (Box 16, Folder C)
  - Slide Lists and Notes, Undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Clown Toy (Jaw Harp?), Undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Paintings and drawings of building and ruins, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Paintings and drawings of building and ruins, Undated (Mapcase-folder 2)
  - Diplomas, 1921-1930 (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Sketches and drawings, Undated (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Class of 1930 University of Pennsylvania architectural school photograph, 1930 (Mapcase-folder 3)
- Series V. American Research Institute in Turkey (ARIT) Materials
  - ARIT Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ARIT Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Incorporation Certificate for ARIT, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Turkish Review of Archaeology, 1958-1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Turkish Review of Archaeology, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Turkish Review of Archaeology, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Turkish Review of Archaeology, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Turkish Review of Archaeology, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Turkish Review of Archaeology, 1962-1968 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series VI. American Research Center in Egypt (ARCE) Materials
  - ARCE Egypt Trip, 1949-1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - ARCE Egypt Trip Correspondences, 1949-1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Report on Moving Abu Simbel, 1962-09 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Reports on Moving Abu Simbel, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - News About Abu Simbel/Aswan Dam, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Pharaonic Monuments in the U.A.R. Report, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Egyptian Survey Notebooks, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Restoration Survey Report, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Series VII. American Institute for Architects (AIA) Materials
  - A.H. Detweiler - AIA Fellowship, 1969-05-21 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Archaeological Reports for AIA, 1952-1966 (Box 7, Folder 26)